Guide to the Abraham Singer Papers 1881-1961 (bulk 1920-1961) MSS.255
Fales Library and Special Collections
Abraham Singer Papers
1881-1961
Fales Library and Special Collections
Singer, Abraham, b. 1876
MSS.255
4.34 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 2 oversize flat boxes
Abraham Singer was born in Austria in 1876. He is mainly known as a composer of Jewish folk and popular songs. He served as cantor of Congregation Ahavath Chesed in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn, NY, in 1920 and as chair of Member Committee of the Jewish Ministers Cantors' Association of America in 1936. The collection contains originals and copies of manuscript scores, published sheet music by Singer as well as others, photographs, printing plates, business cards, printed materials, and a scrapbook.
Scope and Content note
The Abraham Singer Papers contains originals and copies of manuscript scores, published sheet music by Singer as well as others, photographs, photogravure and printing plates, business cards, printed material, and a scrapbook. Materials are in English and Yiddish.
Arrangement
Within each series, materials are arranged alphabetically.
Within each series, materials are arranged alphabetically.
Missing Title
Series I: Scores
Series II: Ephemera
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Biographical / Historical
Abraham Singer, born in Austria in 1876, is mainly known as a composer of Jewish folk and popular songs. He served as cantor of Congregation Ahavath Chesed in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn, NY, in 1920 and as chair of Member Committee of the Jewish Ministers Cantors' Association of America in 1936.
Scrapbooks.; Black-and-white photographs.; Business cards.; Manuscripts for publication.; Jewish composers -- United States; Journals (periodicals); Concerts |z New York (State) |z New York |v Programs.; Scores.; Typescripts; Sheet music.; Photogravures (prints); Printing plates.; Secunda, Sholom, 1894-1974; Carus, Paul "Paisele"
- Series I: Scores, 1914-1949
  - Subseries A: Manuscript Scores and Copies, undated
    - "Ah bekoshe", undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "A yid darf gehn in shul" 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "A yid darf gehn in shul" 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Chanuko in purim" folder, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Der chazen un di shul", undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Di naye velt", undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Ezro Hasoifeir", undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Folder of handwritten scores I, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Folder of handwritten scores II, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "Installation", undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "Mozel-tov", undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "Mazel tov" copy, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "Mein zeidn's cholem", undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Mi shebeirach", undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "No. I" folder, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "Shabbos oif der nacht", undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "Sholom-sholom Yisroel", undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "Sim sholom" + copy, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Songs" folder, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "T'kah B'shofor", undated (Box 1, Folder 20, Folder 24)
  - Subseries B: Published Scores by Abraham Singer, 1930-1949
    - "Bar-mizva", 1932 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Der Freilicher yid", 1930 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Die 3 Shlumiels", 1935 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Dos finfte gebot", 1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Dos fleshil", 1940 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Fun eins bis tzwelf", 1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "Ganuvium amul.....un heint!", 1932 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "In dem nayem beis hamikdosh", 1949 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - "Main zeiden's cholem", 1936 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "Seichel un mazel", 1930 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "Shabos kodesh", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "Zachrenu Lechaiyim", 1939 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Subseries C: Published Scores by Others, 1914-1949
    - "Die Letvishe Shtetle", 1923 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Mother is you best friend", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "Oif'n Pripetshok", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "And the angels sing", 1939 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - "Bei mir bist du shon", 1937 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "Beim thilim", 1933 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "Der rebe gewolt keineretz yisroel fohr'n", 1929 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - "The driver", 1922 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - "The house I live in", 1942 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "Mir yiden mit unzer torah", 1949 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "A shepher, a dreamer," "a prayer", 1933 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - "Soldiers of Israel", 1948 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "A story, or habein yakir li", 1934 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "Zait gebentsht choson-kaloh", 1949 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Series II: Ephemera, 1881-1961
  - Envelope of handwritten documents, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Business cards, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cantor's Journal, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Cantor's Journal, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Chanuka concert program, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Constitution of the first yezierzaner sick ben. ass'n, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "Constitution of the jewish ministers cantors association of america", 1926 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "Die feder--the pen", 1934 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Handwritten list, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Photographs, 1935, 1961, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "Prayers and blessings of Israel", 1881 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Printed photograph of Abraham Singer, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Typescript eulogy form, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Typescript letter from rev. Seymour S. Hirschman, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Bits and Pieces" - handwritten document in Yiddish, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Unidentified typescript document, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Wedding anniversary form, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Tablet and loose manuscripts, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Home and School Tablet, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "Cantor chorus leader" journal, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - First yezierzaner 35th anniversary, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - First yezierzaner 50th anniversary, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - First yezierzaner 60th anniversary, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Jewish ministers cantors association of america fortieth anniversary journal, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Jewish ministers cantors' association of america, inc. golden jubilee journal, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - A freilicher yid 2p metro, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Seichel un mazel 2p metro, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photogravure plate of Abraham Singer I, undated (Box 4)
  - Photogravure plate of Abraham Singer II, undated (Box 4)
  - Photogravure plate of Abraham Singer and others, undated (Box 4)